<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Architecture is not structure. It is judgment under uncertainty. on Gábor — Essays on Software Architecture, Judgment and Change</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Architecture is not structure. It is judgment under uncertainty. on Gábor — Essays on Software Architecture, Judgment and Change</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.154.3</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From Code to Systems: The Three Levels of Thinking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/three-levels-of-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/three-levels-of-thinking/</guid>
      <description>Why many architectural debates fail before they start — not because of disagreement, but because participants are reasoning at different conceptual levels without realizing it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Degrees of Freedom of a System</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/degrees-of-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/degrees-of-freedom/</guid>
      <description>A way to think about flexibility as a structural property rather than a personality trait, and why systems lose their ability to change long before anyone notices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architecture Should Grow, Not Mutate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/architecture-should-grow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/architecture-should-grow/</guid>
      <description>How irreversible decisions quietly accumulate, why “refactoring the whole thing” is rarely possible, and what it means for architecture to gain mass over time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling Is Not Evil — It’s a Commitment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/coupling-is-commitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/coupling-is-commitment/</guid>
      <description>Why eliminating coupling is neither realistic nor desirable, and how the real architectural mistake is failing to recognize which commitments you are making permanent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simplicity Takes Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/simplicity-takes-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/simplicity-takes-work/</guid>
      <description>Why simple systems are not born but constructed, and how most complexity is not a technical failure but a cognitive one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I write about software architecture, systems thinking, and the subtle failures that occur long before anything breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site is not a blog. It is a public thinking surface — a place to reason carefully about change, judgment, and how complexity accumulates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details will appear here soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
